When I learnt driving,
my dad helped me change gears
and helped me become a better driver.
But the learning curve stopped there.
Although, this seems to be a trivial problem,
it avalanches into a problem of environmental and national concern,
where thousands of litres of fuel are wasted
worth lakhs of rupees.
There's always advancement in technology with time
but what we see on the road,
is a technology of the past.
So, we wanted to make changes to the
very fundamental element of the driving hierarchy.
So what if there was someone
to fill the shoes of a driving expert,
sitting next to you, guiding you,
monitoring your car's health all the time,
saving you from having a huge dent in your pocket.
But, this seems to converge to a simple solution
of having a driving assistant,
which is no different from a rulebook.
But what we are dealing with is a real-time problem
which requires real-time data analysed
taking all possible factors into consideration
which a normal rulebook cannot do.
This is where we came up with the idea of AutoNimbus
where data collected from a car using On-Board Diagnostics
is directly sent to the cloud,
processed using optimized machine learning algorithms
is fed back to the user as useful information.
Speed-breaker detection, Road condition detection
Fault detection system, advanced Fleet Mangagement System (FMS)
Gear recommendation and best-route calculation
are minute, but significant things that can
completely rewire the way we drive
and go one level up in increasing fuel efficiency
and drastically bring down fuel and maintenance costs.
Adding to that, on a larger scale,
it even brings down traffic congestion to a larger extent
resulting in more organized and safer roads
saving more time and fuel.
All these recommendations are fed to the user
using a smart-phone application
thus, completing the whole cycle.
Rolling out this idea on a large scale,
stresses on the need for a more reliable,
secure and robust OBD Scanner
which can connect directly to the cloud
in addition to having a more reliable and
stable system on the cloud.
We are planning to make such proprietary OBDs
and have tie-ups with all auto-majors
to reach out with the masses and to
bring about a complete change on Indian roads.